<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/</id>
	<title>Fabrice Moll</title>
	<link rel="self" href="https://www.fabmoll.be/" />
	<rights>2022</rights>
	<updated>2022-01-24T10:02:19Z</updated>
	<entry>
		<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/XiaomiAirPurifierInJeedom</id>
		<title>Add the Xiaomi Air Purifier 3C in Jeedom</title>
		<link href="https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/XiaomiAirPurifierInJeedom" />
		<updated>2022-01-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;The Xiaomi air purifier is a wifi device and to be able to use it in Jeedom you'll need to extract its token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's possible to extract the token by using an old version of the Mi-Home app or using various strange manipulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me it never worked and by chance I found the &lt;a href="https://github.com/PiotrMachowski/Xiaomi-cloud-tokens-extractor" target="_blank"&gt;Xiaomi Cloud tokens extractor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before to use it, you need to add your purifier in the Mi-Home app and then you can execute the &amp;quot;token_extractor.exe&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tool will ask you to enter your Mi-Home login, your password and the server to use.  The last information isn't mandatory and if omitted the tool will scan all countries and will list different information about your devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purifier we just need to get the token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I've the Xiaomi Home plugin in Jeedom I thought it would be easy to add my new toy but it never worked (the information returned by the commands were always empty).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few searches, I found the &lt;a href="https://github.com/rytilahti/python-miio" target="_blank"&gt;miiocli&lt;/a&gt; tool that can be installed on your Jeedom host (you'll be able to see a list of compatible devices on the Github page).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First connect via SSH to your Jeedom host and execute the following command to install the JQ tool (used to manipulate JSON structure)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;sudo apt-get install jq -y
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you can install the miiocli tool:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;sudo apt-get install libffi-dev libssl-dev -y
sudo pip3 install python-miio
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be able to see what you can do with the Air Purifier 3C, you can type the help command and it will describe the options and commands you can use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;sudo miiocli airpurifiermb4 --ip [YourPurifierIP] --token [YourPurifierToken] --help
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parameter &amp;quot;airpurifiermb4&amp;quot; is the device type to use with the command and is linked to the &lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Air Purifier 3C&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you validate the previous command, you'll see all the commands available to control your purifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/miiocli-help.png" alt="miiocli-help" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the following screenshot, I added a new script in Jeedom to be able to control my device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/air-purifier-xiaomi-jeedom.png" alt="script-1" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first command is used to get a json with all the information from the purifier (power, air quality, ...) and then I save it in a file on my server (don't forget to set the IP of your purifier and its token).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second command is used to query the json file and get the power value (enter the IP of your Jeedom host).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third command is used to power on the purifier and so on...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you understood the sample, you'll be able to add more commands to get the rest of the information and with a few click you'll have a widget to control your device and I'm sure most of you will have a better design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/air-purifier-widget.png" alt="widget" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;The Xiaomi air purifier is a wifi device and to be able to use it in Jeedom you'll need to extract its token.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/ForceHttpsAccessInApache</id>
		<title>Force HTTPS access in Apache</title>
		<link href="https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/ForceHttpsAccessInApache" />
		<updated>2021-08-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;If you configured a certificate to access your Jeedom with HTTPS and you don't want to let the HTTP access available, you can change your Apache settings to redirect HTTP access to the HTTPS automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll need to ssh on your Jeedom server and edit the following file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;nano /etc/apache2/sites-available/000-default.conf
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The part we want to modify is the virtual host defined for the HTTP port (80)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;&amp;lt;VirtualHost *:80&amp;gt;
        ServerAdmin webmaster&amp;#64;localhost
        DocumentRoot /var/www/html
        ErrorLog /var/www/html/log/http.error
&amp;lt;/VirtualHost&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we'll edit the file to rewrite the HTTP access to the HTTPS access&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;&amp;lt;VirtualHost *:80&amp;gt;
        ServerAdmin webmaster&amp;#64;localhost
        DocumentRoot /var/www/html

        RewriteEngine on
        RewriteCond %{SERVER_NAME} =My.JeedomDomain.com
        RewriteRule ^ https://%{SERVER_NAME}%{REQUEST_URI} [END,QSA,R=permanent]

        ErrorLog /var/www/html/log/http.error
&amp;lt;/VirtualHost&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to replace the &amp;quot;My.JeedomDomain.com&amp;quot; by your actual domain name used to access your Jeedom from outside your network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it's done, you just need to enable the rewrite module and restart Apache:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;a2enmod rewrite
systemctl restart apache2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;If you configured a certificate to access your Jeedom with HTTPS and you don't want to let the HTTP access available, you can change your Apache settings to redirect HTTP access to the HTTPS automatically.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/SecureTheAccessToYourJeedomWithCertbot</id>
		<title>Secure the access to your Jeedom with Certbot</title>
		<link href="https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/SecureTheAccessToYourJeedomWithCertbot" />
		<updated>2021-08-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I created a &lt;a href="/posts/RedirectHTTPPortToJeedom"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on how to redirect the HTTPS external traffic to a Jeedom in a private network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything will work but you'll see in your browser that the website isn't secure.
The reason is that there is no certificate available on your webserver (on your Jeedom).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To generate, use and auto renew a certificate we'll use &lt;a href="https://certbot.eff.org/" target="_blank"&gt;CertBot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certbot is a free, open source software tool for automatically using Let’s Encrypt certificates on manually-administrated websites to enable HTTPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certbot is made by the Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF), a 501(c)3 nonprofit based in San Francisco, CA, that defends digital privacy, free speech, and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, open a SSH connection to your Jeedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install snapd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;sudo snap install core; sudo snap refresh core
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install Certbot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;sudo snap install --classic certbot
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check if you can run the certbot command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;sudo ln -s /snap/bin/certbot /usr/bin/certbot
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get a certificate and have certbot automatically change your Apache configuration to serve it and to turn on HTTPS access in a single step, use the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;sudo certbot --apache
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The certbot comes with a cron to automatically renew your certificate. But if you want to check if the auto renewal is working, you can use this command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;sudo certbot renew --dry-run
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it completes without errors, your certificate will be renewed automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note that your HTTP(80) and HTTPS(443) port must be opened&lt;/strong&gt; or the auto renewal will not work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you can try to access your Jeedom with the HTTPS url and you'll see that the browser will display that the connection is &amp;quot;secure&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a wise man said once:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;HTTPS &amp;amp; SSL doesn&amp;#39;t mean &amp;quot;trust this.&amp;quot; It means &amp;quot;this is private.&amp;quot; You may be having a private conversation with Satan.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Scott Hanselman (&amp;#64;shanselman) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/shanselman/status/187572289724887041?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 4, 2012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that you'll need to change your Jeedom configuration to add the HTTPS URL (and port) to be able to use the HTTPS URL to access Jeedom.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I created a &lt;a href="/posts/RedirectHTTPPortToJeedom"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on how to redirect the HTTPS external traffic to a Jeedom in a private network.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/RedirectHTTPPortToJeedom</id>
		<title>Redirect HTTP/HTTPS port to your Jeedom</title>
		<link href="https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/RedirectHTTPPortToJeedom" />
		<updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;In the previous blog &lt;a href="/posts/CreateADynHostToAccessJeedom"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; we saw how to create a custom domain name to point to our public IP address.
The main goal was to be able to access our Jeedom from outside our private network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you just type your public IP address or use the new custom domain name to access Jeedom you'll just hit your modem or firewall and they'll not know what do to with the traffic. And you can be sure the traffic will not go to your Jeedom by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're using a Dream Machine Pro (controller 6.2.26) you can redirect the HTTP/HTTPS traffic to your Jeedom by following these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open your Dream Machine Network Manager web page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to Advanced features - Advanced Gateway Settings and click on the Create a new Port Forwarding button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fill in the form as below and validate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/NewPortForwardingRule.png" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can repeat the process to redirect the HTTPS port (443).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if you enter your custom domain in a browser, you'll be able to access your Jeedom in your private network&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;In the previous blog &lt;a href="/posts/CreateADynHostToAccessJeedom"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; we saw how to create a custom domain name to point to our public IP address.
The main goal was to be able to access our Jeedom from outside our private network.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/CreateADynHostToAccessJeedom</id>
		<title>Create a DynHost to access your Jeedom</title>
		<link href="https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/CreateADynHostToAccessJeedom" />
		<updated>2021-07-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;If you want to access your Jeedom from outside your private network, you can do it using your public IP address or using a custom domain name pointing to your public IP address (if the HTTP or HTTPS port is opened).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me and maybe for you, it's easier to remember a custom domain name and I decided to go with one on &lt;a href="https://www.ovh.com/" target="_blank"&gt;OVH&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have my custom domain I would like to use it to access my Jeedom and trust me or not, I didn't know it was so simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="create-a-new-user"&gt;Create a new user&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/OVHCreateUser.png" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go in the DynHost menu and choose to create a username.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/CreateUserOVHDetail.png" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter a username suffix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the sub-domain that you want to define to point to your Jeedom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define a password to use with your username and confirm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="create-a-dynhostrecord"&gt;Create a DynHostRecord&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it's done, you can add a new DynHost record and re-enter the sub-domain name you choosed earlier, enter the target IP (the public IP address of your Jeedom) and confirm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/DynHostRecord.png" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/DynHostRecordDetail.png" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you want to know your public IP address you can go to &lt;a href="https://whatismyipaddress.com/" target="_blank"&gt;whatismyipaddress&lt;/a&gt; and copy the address displayed in the IPv4 field.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an upcoming blog &lt;a href="/posts/RedirectHTTPPortToJeedom"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, we'll see how to automatically refresh your public IP address to DynHost (if you don't have a fixed IP address) and how to redirect incoming traffic on the HTTP port to your Jeedom.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;If you want to access your Jeedom from outside your private network, you can do it using your public IP address or using a custom domain name pointing to your public IP address (if the HTTP or HTTPS port is opened).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/CSScurrentColorValue</id>
		<title>CSS currentColor value</title>
		<link href="https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/CSScurrentColorValue" />
		<updated>2021-07-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I started to learn CSS and HTML.  I already played with CSS and HTML but I had a very very limited knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I don't like to repeat a code or a property value, I found recently that you can apply a color (defined once) in different properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's see an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-css"&gt;div {
    color: blue;
    border: 1px solid currentColor;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;strong&gt;currentColor&lt;/strong&gt; property you indicate that you'll use the value of the color property in other properties that accept a color value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my example, the border color will be blue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can even use it in a cascade:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-css"&gt;body {
    color: blue;
}
div {
     border: 1px solid currentColor;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I started to learn CSS and HTML.  I already played with CSS and HTML but I had a very very limited knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/UpdateJeedomFromVersion4_0_xTo4_1_x</id>
		<title>Update Jeedom from version 4.0.x to 4.1.x</title>
		<link href="https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/UpdateJeedomFromVersion4_0_xTo4_1_x" />
		<updated>2021-01-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, Mr. Hunt, this is not Mission: Difficult, its Mission: Impossible. Difficult should be a walk in the park for you. - &lt;em&gt;Boss, Mission: Impossible 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, a simple update is harder than you think.
Since years, I've a &lt;a href="https://www.jeedom.com/en/" target="_blank"&gt;Jeedom&lt;/a&gt; running on a Raspberry 3B+ and the last Jeedom update installed is the version 4.0.x hosted in a Debian 9 Stretch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I saw that the Jeedom 4.1.x was available with some really nice &lt;a href="https://doc.jeedom.com/en_US/core/4.1/changelog" target="_blank"&gt;improvements&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The condition to be able to install this version is to have the Debian 10 Buster installed.
As we can read in the install &lt;a href="https://doc.jeedom.com/en_US/installation/rpi" target="_blank"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;, the best thing to do is to backup your Jeedom and install everything from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's what I did, downloaded the ISO x86, burned the SDCard, booted on it and installed Jeedom with the command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right after that, I restored my Jeedom backup (I'll not describe that part here).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the fun part begins: Boot from the SSD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you check some websites, you'll read that you &lt;strong&gt;just&lt;/strong&gt; need to install Debian on the SSD, plug it in the Raspberry and restart the device to boot from the SSD.  But there are lies! (It was in my case)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best thing I could find was to clone my SDCard to my SSD and it was really easy with the &lt;a href="https://github.com/billw2/rpi-clone" target="_blank"&gt;rpi-clone&lt;/a&gt; script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;rpi-clone is a shell script that is for cloning a running Raspberry Pi booted source disk (SD card or USB disk) to a destination disk which will be bootable. Destination disks are SD cards in the SD card slot or a USB card reader, USB flash disks, or USB hard drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, clone the repository and copy the setup in your /usr/local/sbin directory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;git clone https://github.com/billw2/rpi-clone.git
cd rpi-clone
sudo cp rpi-clone rpi-clone-setup /usr/local/sbin
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop the following services:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;sudo service mysql stop
sudo service cron stop
sudo service apache2 stop
sudo service nginx stop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connect your SSD to your Raspberry and clone your SDCard to your SSD:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;rpi-clone sda -f
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it's done, you can restart the services:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;sudo service mysql start
sudo service cron start
sudo service apache2 start
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing to do is to configure your Raspberry to be able to boot on the USB port.
For that, you'll need to backup your current config.txt file, set the boot mode and then restart the Raspberry:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;cp /boot/config.txt /boot/config.txt.old
echo program_usb_boot_mode=1 | sudo tee -a /boot/config.txt
sudo reboot
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your device restarted, you can check if the boot mode is set to boot on USB with the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;vcgencmd otp_dump | grep 17
&amp;gt;17:3020000a
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it returns 17:3020000a, the setting has been taken into account.
Now we need to change the boot config to be able to boot on the SSD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the PARTUUID from your SSD (/dev/sda2):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;sudo blkid
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/subo-blkid.jpg" alt="sudo blkid" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backup your current cmdline file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;sudo cp /boot/cmdline.txt /boot/cmdline.txt.bak
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit the cmdline file and replace the PARTUUID with the value we copied from the sudo blkid command, save and quit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;sudo nano /boot/cmdline.txt
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/cmdline.jpg" alt="cmdline edit" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it's done, you can reboot again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;sudo reboot
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the reboot, the following command should display the /dev/sda2 device:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;findmnt -n -o SOURCE /
&amp;gt; /dev/sda2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost finished, now you need to change fstab to use the PARTUUID from your SSD device, save, quit and reboot again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;sudo nano /etc/fstab
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/fstab.jpg" alt="fstab" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;sudo reboot
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is done to create a new partition on your SSD. As you'll see later, the partition size on your SSD is the same as your SDCard. Here we want to use the entire SSD disk size:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/fdisk.jpg" alt="fdisk" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll need to reboot again when the partition is created.  This time it may take a little longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not yet finished, now you need to resize the partition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/resize2fs.jpg" alt="fdisk" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If everything went well, you should see the new partition size with the df command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;df -h
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/df.jpg" alt="df" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;Well, Mr. Hunt, this is not Mission: Difficult, its Mission: Impossible. Difficult should be a walk in the park for you. - &lt;em&gt;Boss, Mission: Impossible 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/RefreshTheXiaomiDoorSensorStatusWithAScenario</id>
		<title>Refresh the Xiaomi door sensor status with a scenario in Jeedom</title>
		<link href="https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/RefreshTheXiaomiDoorSensorStatusWithAScenario" />
		<updated>2021-01-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;Since the beginning I've never had an issue with my Xiaomi sensors but for no reason one of them started to not update his status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I close the door Jeedom still displays the door as opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn't find the reason and I discovered that a simple refresh command could reset the status and display the right information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't want to refresh the status manually, you can do it with a scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, create a triggered scenario on the Xiaomi sensor for the &lt;em&gt;opening&lt;/em&gt; command and give a name to your scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then in the scenario definition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add a &lt;em&gt;Sleep&lt;/em&gt; action for 10 seconds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add a &lt;em&gt;refresh&lt;/em&gt; command from your Xiaomi sensor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add an &lt;em&gt;IF&lt;/em&gt; condition and check if the &lt;em&gt;opening&lt;/em&gt; command value is equal to 1 (open)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add a &lt;em&gt;THEN&lt;/em&gt; condition to execute your current scenario&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the status changes, the scenario will wait 10 seconds and then execute the sensor refresh command. If the status is still equal to 1 (open), it will execute again the current scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/RefreshtheXiaomidoorsensorstatuswithascenario.jpg" alt="Enable Use Conditional Forwarding" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if the door is closed and the status is not up to date the scenario will update it after 10 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;Since the beginning I've never had an issue with my Xiaomi sensors but for no reason one of them started to not update his status.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/HowToDisplayDeviceNameInYourPiHole</id>
		<title>How to display device name in your Pi-hole</title>
		<link href="https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/HowToDisplayDeviceNameInYourPiHole" />
		<updated>2021-01-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;When your &lt;a href="https://pi-hole.net/" target="_blank"&gt;Pi-hole&lt;/a&gt; doesn't act as a DHCP server (because you already have another one) you'll able to see only the IP addresses of the devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not really user-friendly when you need to analyze the log of the Pi-Hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But don't be afraid, there is a &lt;span style="color:green"&gt;solution&lt;/span&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be able to see the device name, you just need to enable the &lt;strong&gt;Use Conditional Forwarding&lt;/strong&gt; setting in the Settings - DNS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/HowtodisplaydevicenameinyourPi-hole.jpg" alt="Enable Use Conditional Forwarding" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the option is enabled, enter the local network to use and the IP address of your DHCP server as described in the screenshot, save and it's done. It's magic.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;When your &lt;a href="https://pi-hole.net/" target="_blank"&gt;Pi-hole&lt;/a&gt; doesn't act as a DHCP server (because you already have another one) you'll able to see only the IP addresses of the devices.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/AcceptDNSQueriesToSpecificIPAddressesWithinYourDreamMachinePro</id>
		<title>Accept DNS queries to specific IP addresses within your Dream Machine Pro</title>
		<link href="https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/AcceptDNSQueriesToSpecificIPAddressesWithinYourDreamMachinePro" />
		<updated>2020-12-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;Holidays are nice when you want to try something new.&lt;br /&gt;
In my case, I wanted to install a &lt;a href="https://pi-hole.net/" target="_blank"&gt;Pi-Hole&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
If you never heard about Pi-Hole, it's a DNS sinkhole that protects your devices from unwanted content, without installing any client-side software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My post isn't a &lt;em&gt;How-to&lt;/em&gt; install/configure/... the thing.&lt;br /&gt;
Here we'll see how to create firewall rules on the Dream Machine Pro to refuse all DNS queries except the one to the Pi-Hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do is to create two groups in the firewall settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One to specify the DNS port to block (53) and another one to contain the IP addresses that will be used to accept DNS queries (The Pi-Hole address and maybe some other DNS addresses).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use groups to be able to add/remove address or port as I wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First group&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name: DNS Port&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type: Port&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Port value: 53&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second group&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name: DNS to Accept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type: Address IPV4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Address: The address of your PI-Hole and maybe some other public DNS addresses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it's done, we need to create two firewall rules.  One to block all outbound traffic to the port 53 and another one to accept all outbound traffic to the port 53 but only for the addresses we trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First rule&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name: Accept DNS Group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rule applied: Before predefined rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Action: Accept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source Type: Address/Port group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source IPv4 Address Group: Any&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source Port Group: Any&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Destination Type: Address/Port group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Destination IPv4 Address Group: DNS to Accept (the second group we created)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Destination Port Group: DNS Port (the first group we created)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second rule&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name: Drop other DNS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rule applied: Before predefined rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Action: Drop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source Type: Address/Port group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source IPv4 Address Group: Any&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source Port Group: Any&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Destination Type: Address/Port group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Destination IPv4 Address Group: Any&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Destination Port Group: DNS Port (the first group we created)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these rules, the devices connected to our LAN will only use the DNS we trust and if a malware tries to bypass our DNS, it will be blocked by the second firewall rule.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;Holidays are nice when you want to try something new.&lt;br&gt;
In my case, I wanted to install a &lt;a href="https://pi-hole.net/" target="_blank"&gt;Pi-Hole&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
If you never heard about Pi-Hole, it's a DNS sinkhole that protects your devices from unwanted content, without installing any client-side software.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/ChangeProximusInternetPassword</id>
		<title>Change Proximus Internet password</title>
		<link href="https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/ChangeProximusInternetPassword" />
		<updated>2020-12-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;In some cases you'll handle the PPPoE connection in your router.&lt;br /&gt;
The main reason is to connect to the Proximus network from your router and let your personal hardware manage the DHCP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know your login and password, it's really easy.  But if like me, you lost your original password / don't remember it / never saved it in your favorite password tool / ... you're doomed.  Or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proximus made it simple, you can login on their website and in the MyProducts section you need to select your &amp;quot;Internet&amp;quot; product.&lt;br /&gt;
From there you'll be able to define a new password without the need to enter your old password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/ChangeProximusInternetPassword-ProximusLogin.jpg" alt="Proximus Password change" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the password is changed, it will take effect within two hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first error was to change it too in my modem -&amp;gt; No more Internet at home.&lt;br /&gt;
In fact you can use the old password as long as Proximus didn't validate your new password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two hours later... No Internet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wife_acceptance_factor" target="_blank"&gt;WAF&lt;/a&gt; was aligned with the two hours but not with more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had two solutions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try a new password on Proximus website (and wait two more hours)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact the Support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't remember my web search but I found a ticket about the PPPoE connection with the Proximus modem and the new password rule.&lt;br /&gt;
In fact, the new password &lt;strong&gt;must be eight characters long and it must only contain alphanumeric characters&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing I didn't say is that I used a password generator to have something complex on my first try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So before to call the Support, I changed my password to match the rule (on Proximus website and in my router) and it worked right away.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;In some cases you'll handle the PPPoE connection in your router.&lt;br&gt;
The main reason is to connect to the Proximus network from your router and let your personal hardware manage the DHCP.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/ChangeStatusBarColorInXamarinForms</id>
		<title>Change the status bar color in your Xamarin.Forms app</title>
		<link href="https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/ChangeStatusBarColorInXamarinForms" />
		<updated>2020-10-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;It's the second time I need to change the status bar color in a Xamarin.Forms (Android) and I didn't remember how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I don't want to search it again, I decided to add the information here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The status bar is the top part of the application where you can find the battery level, the network status,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/ChangeStatusBarColorInXamarinForms.jpg" alt="Folder structure" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your Android project, just add the following line in the styles.xml file and use the color you like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-xml"&gt;&amp;lt;item name=&amp;quot;android:statusBarColor&amp;quot;&amp;gt;#3F4550&amp;lt;/item&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;It's the second time I need to change the status bar color in a Xamarin.Forms (Android) and I didn't remember how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/FrameHeightRequestNotApplied</id>
		<title>Frame HeightRequest not applied</title>
		<link href="https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/FrameHeightRequestNotApplied" />
		<updated>2020-01-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;For each of my items in the ListView, I wanted to display the title of the show and the remaining episodes.&lt;br /&gt;
But it can be really difficult to see the label on an image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A solution I used in my previous Windows Phone app was to add a border with a background color. So I decided to use the same tip with the &lt;strong&gt;Frame&lt;/strong&gt; control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;&amp;lt;Frame Grid.Row=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; HeightRequest=&amp;quot;22&amp;quot; VerticalOptions=&amp;quot;End&amp;quot;  BackgroundColor=&amp;quot;#80000000&amp;quot; &amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;StackLayout Orientation=&amp;quot;Horizontal&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Label Grid.Row=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;  Text=&amp;quot;{Binding Title}&amp;quot; TextColor=&amp;quot;#FFFFFF&amp;quot; Margin=&amp;quot;5,0,0,0&amp;quot; LineBreakMode=&amp;quot;TailTruncation&amp;quot; 
                    HorizontalOptions=&amp;quot;StartAndExpand&amp;quot; FontAttributes=&amp;quot;Bold&amp;quot; FontSize=&amp;quot;Subtitle&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Label Grid.Row=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;  Text=&amp;quot;{Binding User.Remaining}&amp;quot; TextColor=&amp;quot;#FFFFFF&amp;quot; Margin=&amp;quot;0,0,5,0&amp;quot; HorizontalOptions=&amp;quot;End&amp;quot; 
                    FontAttributes=&amp;quot;Bold&amp;quot; FontSize=&amp;quot;Subtitle&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/StackLayout&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/Frame&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/FrameHeightRequestnotappliedBadHeightRequest.jpg" alt="Wrong HeightRequest" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
As you can see, the HeightRequest seems to be ignored. It's bigger than expected. In fact, the Frame control has a &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/api/Xamarin.Forms.Frame?view=xamarin-forms" target="_blank"&gt;default padding&lt;/a&gt; of 20.
&lt;p&gt;To have the expected result, you just need to set the Frame's &lt;strong&gt;Padding to 0&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;&amp;lt;Frame Grid.Row=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; HeightRequest=&amp;quot;22&amp;quot; VerticalOptions=&amp;quot;End&amp;quot;  BackgroundColor=&amp;quot;#80000000&amp;quot; Padding=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;StackLayout Orientation=&amp;quot;Horizontal&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Label Grid.Row=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;  Text=&amp;quot;{Binding Title}&amp;quot; TextColor=&amp;quot;#FFFFFF&amp;quot; Margin=&amp;quot;5,0,0,0&amp;quot; LineBreakMode=&amp;quot;TailTruncation&amp;quot; 
                    HorizontalOptions=&amp;quot;StartAndExpand&amp;quot; FontAttributes=&amp;quot;Bold&amp;quot; FontSize=&amp;quot;Subtitle&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Label Grid.Row=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;  Text=&amp;quot;{Binding User.Remaining}&amp;quot; TextColor=&amp;quot;#FFFFFF&amp;quot; Margin=&amp;quot;0,0,5,0&amp;quot; HorizontalOptions=&amp;quot;End&amp;quot; 
                    FontAttributes=&amp;quot;Bold&amp;quot; FontSize=&amp;quot;Subtitle&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/StackLayout&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/Frame&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now the HeightRequest defined is applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/FrameHeightRequestnotappliedGoodHeightRequest.jpg" alt="Wrong HeightRequest" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;For each of my items in the ListView, I wanted to display the title of the show and the remaining episodes.&lt;br&gt;
But it can be really difficult to see the label on an image.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/SyntaxHighlightingInWyam</id>
		<title>Syntax Highlighting In Wyam</title>
		<link href="https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/SyntaxHighlightingInWyam" />
		<updated>2020-01-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;In my previous blog &lt;a href="/posts/RowHeightInListViewItemTemplate"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; I saw that the syntax highlighting was weird on a phone.&lt;br /&gt;
A carriage return was added automatically instead of taking advantage of the &lt;em&gt;power&lt;/em&gt; of a scrollbar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/SyntaxHighlightingInWyamCarriageReturn.jpg" alt="Syntax with carriage return" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
To avoid the carriage return and let the scrollbar work as expected we need to override the CSS with the following style:
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-css"&gt;pre code {
        white-space: pre;
        word-wrap: normal;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just create the following folder structure in your input directory, create a file named &lt;strong&gt;override.css&lt;/strong&gt; and add the &lt;strong&gt;pre code&lt;/strong&gt; style in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/SyntaxHighlightingInWyamFolderStructure.jpg" alt="Folder structure" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Build your blog and start the preview to see the result.
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/SyntaxHighlightingInWyamWiithScrollbar.jpg" alt="Folder structure" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;In my previous blog &lt;a href="/posts/RowHeightInListViewItemTemplate"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; I saw that the syntax highlighting was weird on a phone.&lt;br&gt;
A carriage return was added automatically instead of taking advantage of the &lt;em&gt;power&lt;/em&gt; of a scrollbar.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/RowHeightInListViewItemTemplate</id>
		<title>Row height in ListView ItemTemplate</title>
		<link href="https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/RowHeightInListViewItemTemplate" />
		<updated>2020-01-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;In my App I wanted to have a view for my TV shows.&lt;br /&gt;
As I have a WPF and Windows Phone background, I tried to set the row height on the Grid RowDefinition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;&amp;lt;ListView ItemsSource=&amp;quot;{Binding Shows}&amp;quot; VerticalOptions=&amp;quot;FillAndExpand&amp;quot; &amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;ListView.ItemTemplate&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;DataTemplate&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;ViewCell&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;Grid&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;Grid.ColumnDefinitions&amp;gt;
                         &amp;lt;ColumnDefinition Width=&amp;quot;*&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;/Grid.ColumnDefinitions&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;Grid.RowDefinitions&amp;gt;								
                         &amp;lt;RowDefinition Height=&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;/Grid.RowDefinitions&amp;gt;
                    
                    &amp;lt;ffimageloading:CachedImage Grid.Row=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; Source=&amp;quot;{Binding Image.Banner}&amp;quot;
                        Aspect=&amp;quot;AspectFill&amp;quot;							
                        RetryCount= &amp;quot;3&amp;quot;
                        RetryDelay= &amp;quot;600&amp;quot;
                        HeightRequest=&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;
                        DownsampleToViewSize = &amp;quot;true&amp;quot;	/&amp;gt;
                        
                    &amp;lt;Frame Grid.Row=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; HeightRequest=&amp;quot;20&amp;quot; VerticalOptions=&amp;quot;End&amp;quot; Padding=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;
                        BackgroundColor=&amp;quot;#80000000&amp;quot; &amp;gt;
                        &amp;lt;StackLayout Orientation=&amp;quot;Horizontal&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
                            &amp;lt;Label Grid.Row=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;  Text=&amp;quot;{Binding Title}&amp;quot; TextColor=&amp;quot;#FFFFFF&amp;quot; Margin=&amp;quot;5,0,0,0&amp;quot;
                            LineBreakMode=&amp;quot;TailTruncation&amp;quot; HorizontalOptions=&amp;quot;StartAndExpand&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
                            &amp;lt;Label Grid.Row=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;  Text=&amp;quot;{Binding User.Remaining}&amp;quot; TextColor=&amp;quot;#FFFFFF&amp;quot;
                            Margin=&amp;quot;0,0,5,0&amp;quot; HorizontalOptions=&amp;quot;End&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
                        &amp;lt;/StackLayout&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;/Frame&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;/Grid&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;/ViewCell&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/DataTemplate&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/ListView.ItemTemplate&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ListView&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the result was completely wrong. The black frame is too big and the show title is not displayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/RowHeightInListViewItemTemplate-WrongHeight.jpg" alt="WrongRowHeight" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to change the row definition of the Grid to &lt;strong&gt;Auto&lt;/strong&gt; and let the image take the needed height but the result was the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, you have to set the &lt;strong&gt;HasUnevenRows&lt;/strong&gt; property of the ListView to &lt;strong&gt;True&lt;/strong&gt; to force the row height otherwise the ListView will use his default row height size (and the behaviour will be really strange).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;&amp;lt;ListView ItemsSource=&amp;quot;{Binding Shows}&amp;quot;  VerticalOptions=&amp;quot;FillAndExpand&amp;quot; HasUnevenRows=&amp;quot;True&amp;quot; &amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For iOS, I read that you have to set the &lt;strong&gt;RowHeight&lt;/strong&gt; on the ListView or the size will be ignored. I couldn't verify the behaviour but since my items have the same height, I can set the &lt;strong&gt;RowHeight&lt;/strong&gt; property on the ListView and remove the &lt;strong&gt;HasUnevenRows&lt;/strong&gt; property to use its default value (False).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;&amp;lt;ListView ItemsSource=&amp;quot;{Binding Shows}&amp;quot;  VerticalOptions=&amp;quot;FillAndExpand&amp;quot; RowHeight=&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here is the result:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="../images/RowHeightInListViewItemTemplate-GoodHeight.jpg" alt="WrongRowHeight" align="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;In my App I wanted to have a view for my TV shows.&lt;br&gt;
As I have a WPF and Windows Phone background, I tried to set the row height on the Grid RowDefinition.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<id>https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/first-post</id>
		<title>A new adventure</title>
		<link href="https://www.fabmoll.be/posts/first-post" />
		<updated>2019-11-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;Yeah! The first post.&lt;br /&gt;
I really wanted to start my blog and I finally decided to install everything to do so.&lt;br /&gt;
Even if you only see a simple page, I had a fun time with my Azure Pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source code of my blog is hosted on &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/devops/" target="_blank"&gt;Azure DevOps&lt;/a&gt; and with one push to the Git repository, the Pipeline compiles my blog and publishes the result automatically to my GitHub Pages. It's magic!&lt;br /&gt;
Like you can see, there are still several things to configure on this blog but if I don't start now I'll never start!&lt;br /&gt;
Enjoy ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;Yeah! The first post.&lt;br&gt;
I really wanted to start my blog and I finally decided to install everything to do so.&lt;br&gt;
Even if you only see a simple page, I had a fun time with my Azure Pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
</feed>